<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: LitCrit | Heteroscadasticity]]></title>
  <link href="http://jaime19683.github.com/hetero/blog/categories/litcrit/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jaime19683.github.com/hetero/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-16T20:46:32-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jaime19683.github.com/hetero/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jamie Yeats]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stupid Little Realization Stories]]></title>
    <link href="http://jaime19683.github.com/hetero/blog/2012/03/16/stupid-little-realization-stories/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T20:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jaime19683.github.com/hetero/blog/2012/03/16/stupid-little-realization-stories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The term <strong><em>New Yorker Stories</em></strong> has become a generic one in my family for stories that may or may not have actually been printed in the <em>New Yorker</em> magazine, but that start and end at apparently arbitrary points and vary in tone from glum to worse.</p>




<p>Over a recent weekend I was re-reading Alice Munro&#8217;s collection of short stories, <em>Too Much Happiness</em>, in preparation for a group discussion . When I took a break my wife asked me what the stories were like. After I described one she said, &#8220;Oh, you mean they&#8217;re <em>New Yorker Stories</em>.&#8221;</p>




<p>Later that same weekend I ran across the below from Allison Lurie&#8217;s review of Julian Barnes&#8217; latest in the <a href="http://www.nybooks.com/articles/archives/2011/jun/09/master-downbeat/">NYRB</a>:</p>




<blockquote>
<p>&#8220;Literary fiction, however, now tends to conform to Tom Stoppard’s addition to Miss Prism’s Rule, first stated in Rosencrantz and Guildenstern Are Dead (1966): “The bad end unhappily, the good unluckily. That is what tragedy means.” The scale of the tragedy, of course, varies widely. When we begin a story by a known and admired writer in a known and admired journal, we do not always expect a major disaster, but we know that something unpleasant is going to happen to the main characters, and/or that they will end up understanding something unpleasant about themselves, their friends or family, or the world in general. (Years ago, a Harvard student called Speed Lamkin described the latter tales to me as “stupid little realization stories.”)&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>




<p>This seemed to be a most satisfactory description of the <em>New Yorker Story</em>.   The only opportunity for improvement would be to replace the phrase &#8220;known and admired journal&#8221; with some more explicit reference to the <em>New Yorker</em>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
